Yearning
Excuse me.
Grandpa, I want to eat this.
Sir, you have good a taste.
This is a red bean hairpin,
in Guangdong style.
Tong Er, where are you going?
It's raining outside.
Mother, I'm going to see Liuniang
*Liu: number 6; Niang: used to describe young girls here; The girl might be the sixth child of her family.
Come back soon!
Liuniang, Liuniang!
Little Scholar.
*Scholar: who has passed the entry-level examination to study at a college.
What are you doing here?
Hmm...
T- to show you something good.
What's the good thing exactly?
Show it to me.
Dummy!
You're all wet, come up here!
I thought it was supposed to be precious.
Isn't it just a red bean?
It was not precious at all.
It is not a regular red bean.
It's the red bean from the poem of Wang Wei
*Wang Wei: famous poet, painter from Tang dynasty.
Didn't you heard of Wang Wei's...
..."Yearning"?
Little Scholar,
then can you recite it?
Of course!
Then recite it for me.
If you can't...
... your hand will be hurt
Sure!
The red bean grows in southern lands.
With spring its slender tendrils twine.
Gather for me some more, I pray.
As a symbol of...
...As, as a symbol..
Show me your hand.
Tong Er, Tong Er,
Dinner is ready, come home!
My mother called me, good bye.
The red bean grows in southern lands.
With spring its slender tendrils twine.
Show me your hand.
Little Scholar,
Come here!
What happened?
Got scolded by your teacher?
Don't be sad.
I have something good to give you.
In return for yesterday's gift.
Oops!
Oh, did the teacher hit you?
Open your mouth.
Look,
That's Liuniang.
Hey, ferryman.
Come here.
Here I come.
Selling pears.
Fresh pears!
Wow, the pear smells good.
Hurry up, the food is getting cold.
Wait!
Why are you so late?
Here, let's go.
Hurry up, Yu Yang.
Let's go take a look.
Yes, this is a large wedding.
Yeah, they are such a great match.
You tell me.
Come here.
Hurry up and make the delivery.
Got it, got it.
Be careful!
My pears!
Watch where you are going!!
Sigh
♪ The red bean grows in southern lands. ♪
♪ With spring its slender tendrils twine. ♪
♪ Gather for me some more, I pray. ♪
♪ As a symbol of our fond memories. ♪
♪ The red bean grows in southern lands. ♪*
Take care, Mother.
Travel safely.
*Wang Chutong (1730-1821): other name: Yu Yang. He was born in a poor family but was quiet in mind with few desires. He was summoned by Qianlong Emperor, and ranked as a secondary governor. He worked as the mayor in multiple cities and wrote many books.
In one of his books he wrote: "The color of the red beans is better than the coral, and the girls in the south like jade hairpins with this color."
Red beans, indeed are the symbol of yearning.