New Year's Day
Be careful.
I want some, I want some!
I know how we can get the nice food, come with me.
Come on.
Hurry up.
Don't fool around, come down.
It smells so good!
The one is ready. Take it out.
Sure.
No!
Where are your manners?
Don't take something that doesn't belong to you.
Right?
Virtue is owning up your mistakes.
One for each of you.
Peanuts!
Me first! I was the first!
Master is waiting for you.
Growing napa cabbages, harvesting chives.
Watering the garden and growing vegetables.
Simple and happy lifestyle.
Me first, I was first!
I was first!
Happy new year!
Be careful on the road
-You can leave now
-Sure
Don't run too fast
Tanghulu
How's your family?
Come with me, Mom!
Excuse me.
Happy New Year!
Mom, that tiger looks nice.
Rooster!
So pretty~
Bawcock,
we have so many people in our house.
We didn't prepare anything.
What should we do?
My students being here means they respect me.
Why would dinning manners matter at all?
Dishes are offered on the altar in the first lunar month.
Water caltrops
Water chestnuts
Glutinous rice balls
The self-grown napa cabbage can also be used.
So the hard work throughout the year is worth it.
Please enjoy.
What is this?
Hahaha, this is happy-new-year soup.
Just like Hui, who lives in a poor place, eating simple food.
*Yan Hui: the favorite disciple of Confucius and one of the most revered figures of Confucianism.
Other people can't stand such poor life,
but we can find joy and containment in such life.
How is it?
Delicious!
Teacher, there are fireworks!
Mom, did you see?
Excuse me.
♪ Amid the boom of firecrackers a year has come to an end. ♪
♪ And the spring wind had wafted warm breath to the wine. ♪
♪ While the rising sun shines over each and every household, ♪
♪ People would put up new peachwood charm for the old. ♪
The end